Salvador Luria Papers 1923-1992 Mss.Ms.Coll.39
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by others, 1944-1990; 11 linear feet
  - The Chemical Basis for a Case of Host-Induced Modification in Phage T2, [1963]; Glover, S.W.; Schell, J.; Silver, Simon; Stacey, K.; Symonds, Neville (Box 68)
  - "Some Effects of Radiation, During the Early Part of the Latent Period, on Bacteria Infected with the Phages T2 or T4", Symonds, Neville (Box 68)
  - Research on Viruses in Relation to Tumor Origin, 16 Sep. 1958; Syverton, Jerome T. (Box 68)
  - "[On Science, Scientists, Polticians, and Viet Nam]", 22 Aug. 1966; Szent-Györgyi, Albert (Box 68)
  - Asymmetric Distribution of the Transcribing Regions on the Complementary Strands of Coliphage L DNA, Hradecna, Zdenka; Szybalski, Waclaw; Taylor, Karol (Box 68)
  - Effects of L Infection on Bacterial Synthesis, n.d.; Levinthal, Cyrus; Terzi, Mario (Box 68)
  - Studies on the Mechanism of T4 Interference with Host Metabolism, n.d.; Terzi, Mario (Box 68)
  - Gene Function in Phage S13, n.d.; Tessman, Ethel S. (Box 68)
  - Functional Units of Phage S13: Identification of Two Genes That Determine the Structure of the Phage Coat, n.d.; Tessman, Ethel S.; Tessman, Irwin (Box 68)
  - Mutagenesis and the Functioning of Genetic Material in Phage, Tessman, Irwin (Box 68)
  - The Anatomy of Viral DNA Molecules, n.d.; MacHattie, Lorne A.; Thomas, Charles A., Jr. (Box 68)
  - The Arrangements of Nucleotide Sequences in T2 and T5 Bacteriophage DNA Molecules, Rubinstein, Irwin; Thomas, Charles A., Jr. (Box 69)
  - "The Infection of Sub-Cellular Escherichia Coli, Strain B, with a DNA Preparation from T2 Bacteriophage", n.d.; Fraser, Dean; Mahler, Henry R.; Shug, Austin L.; Thomas, Charles A., Jr. (Box 69)
  - The Nucleotide Composition of Short Segments of DNA Molecules, n.d.; Miyazawa, Yuji; Thomas, Charles A., Jr. (Box 69)
  - The Organization of DNA in Bacteriophage and Bacteria, Thomas, Charles A., Jr. (Box 69)
  - Sedimentation Equilibrium Studies on Intact and Fragmented Bacteriophage DNA, Pinkerton, T.C.; Thomas, Charles A., Jr. (Box 69)
  - Terminal Repetition in Non-Permuted T3 and T7 Phage DNA Molecules, MacHattie, Lorne A.; Ritchie, D.A.; Thomas, Charles A., Jr.; Wensink, P.C. (Box 69)
  - "Origin, Variation and Properties of the Genetic Elements Responsible for Transduction of the LAC"" Characters""", 1961; Ting, Robert Chin-Yao (Box 69)
  - "An Overview of Amphetamines for the Salk Institute Workshop, La Jolla, California, January 22-24, 1970", Jan. 1970; Tinklenberg, Jared R. (Box 69)
  - Differential Effects of Amino Acid Deficiencies on Bacterial Cytochemistry, [1962]; Kolb, Joseph J.; Shockman, Gerald D.; Toennies, Gerrit (Box 69)
  - Choline in the Cell Wall of a Bacterium: Novel Type of Polymer-Linked Choline in Pneumococcus, n.d.; Tomasz, (Box 69)
  - Genetic Structure of Recombinant Chromosomes Formed after Mating in Escherichia Coli K12, n.d.; Tomizawa, Jun-ichi (Box 69)
  - Ordered Synthesis of Proteins During Outgrowth of Spores of B. Cereus T, n.d.; Gorini, Annamaria Torriani; Levinthal, Cyrus (Box 69)
  - Untersuchungen zur Struktur von Heterozygoten Bei Bakteriophagen, 1957; Trautner, Thomas A. (Box 69)
  - Zur Physiologie der Populationsgenetik des Phagen T1, n.d.; Bresch, Carsten, 1921-; Trautner, Thomas A. (Box 69)
  - Stable Expression and Replication of Hepatitis B Virus Genome in an Integrated State in a Human Hepatoma Cell Line Transfected with the Cloned Viral DNA, Fumiyama, Asao; Matsubara, Kenichi; Tsurimoto, Toshiki (Box 69)
  - "Heat as a Danger in Shelters: the High Cost of Blast Shelters: and the Limited Protection They Afford, Ullmann, John E. (Box 69)
  - Blood Groups, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 69)
  - Chromatographic Analysis of DNA and RNA from Bacteria, Unidentified (Box 69)
  - Psychology and Ideology, Unidentified (Box 69)
  - [Review of] The Truth About Cancer by Charles S. Cameron, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 69)
  - Summary of Oc Transduction, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 69)
  - Tris-Glucose Medium, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 69)
  - Ribonucleic Acid Metabolism in Bacterial Cells Destined to Lysogeny, 1965; Ikawa, S.; Toyama, S.; Uetake, Hisao (Box 69)
  - The Requirement for Energy Transducing ATPase for Anaerobic Motility in E. Coli, n.d.; Thipayathasana, Pairorh; Valentine, Raymond C. (Box 69)
  - Harvard Commencement Speech, 5 Jun. 1980; Vance, Cyrus R. (Box 69)
  - Biologia, [1974]; Vitale, Mauricio (Box 69)
  - The Distribution of Tissue Specific Antigens within Centrifugal Fractions of Rat Liver, [1958]; Vogt, Peter (Box 69)
  - [Bibliography], 1958; von Wettstein, Diter (Box 69)
  - Observations on the Kinetics of the Induction of Beta-Galactosidase in Escherichia Coli, Wallenfels, K. (Box 69)
  - The Specificity of the Induction of the Enzymes of the lac Operon in Escherichia Coli, Müller-Hill, B.; Rickenberg, Howard V.; Wallenfels, K. (Box 69)
  - Enzyme Production After Lysis Induction, Signer, Ethan R.; Warner, John and Ethan Signer; Warner, John,d. 1873. (Box 69)
  - The Biological Properties of X-Ray Inactivated Bacteriophage, 1950; Watson, James Dewey, 1928- (Box 69)
  - Nucleic Acid Transfer from Parental to Progeny Bacteriophage, n.d.; Maaløe, Ole; Watson, James D., 1928- (Box 69)
  - Induction of Mutations in Bacterial Viruses, Weigle, Jean J. (Box 70)
  - Lysogenesis of Strain K12 of E. Coli, n.d.; Delbrück, Max; Weigle, Jean J. and Max Delbrück; Weigle, Jean J. (Box 70)
  - Mutual Exclusion between an Infecting Phage and a Carried Phage, Delbrück, Max; Weigle, Jean J. (Box 70)
  - Reports, 1952; Weigle, Jean J. (Box 70)
  - Some Properties of the DNA of a Tumor-Producing Virus, [1963]; Weil, Roger (Box 70)
  - Dual Function of the Lambda Prophage Repressor, n.d.; Gallant, Jonathan A.; Weisberg, Robert A. (Box 70)
  - "Dequalinium, a Topical Antimicrobial Agent, Displays Anticarcinoma Activity Based on Selective Mitochondrial Accumulation", [1985]; Soo Ha, Chul; Weiss, Michael J.; Wong, James R. (Box 70)
  - Novel Diagnostic Modality and Targeted Therapy of Carcinomas, Dec. 1985; Naiman, Charles S.; Weiss, Michael J. (Box 70)
  - Transmembrane Proton Gradient and Colicin K Action, Sep. 1975; Weiss, Michael J. (Box 70)
  - [Lecture Notes], n.d.; Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1908-2002 (Box 70)
  - Report on the Visa Situation, May-52; Weisskopf, Victor Frederick, 1908-2002 (Box 70)
  - On the Impact of the Computer on Society--Lecture, 18 Nov. 1971; Weizenbaum, Joseph (Box 70)
  - Some Comparative Observations on the Behavior of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Animals and in Tissue Culture, [1957]; Wenner, Herbert A. (Box 70)
  - Electron Microscope Observation of Bacteriophage Invasion Processes, n.d.; Fraser, Dean; Williams, Robley C. (Box 70)
  - Mutation-Proof and Mutation-Prone Modes of Survival in Derivatives of Escherichia Coli B Differing in Sensitivity to Ultraviolet Light, 1967; Witkin, Evelyn M. (Box 70)
  - The Microbes--An Introduction, n.d.; Wolfe, R. (Box 70)
  - Characterization of a Polyisoprenoid Compound Functional in O-Antigen Biosynthesis, Dankert, M.; Fennessey, P.; Robbins, P.W.; Wright, A. (Box 70)
  - China Misunderstood, 1966; Wu, Shang-Ying (Box 70)
  - Research Report, Mar. 1969; Wu, Teresa (Box 70)
  - Yeast and Bacterial Cell Protein from Hydrocarbons, 1967; Kawabata, Yasuro; Takahashi, Joji; Yamada, Koichi (Box 70)
  - Integration-Negative (int) Mutants of Lambda Bacteriophage, n.d.; Gottesman, Max E.; Yarmolinsky, Michael (Box 70)
  - Exclusion of RNA Phages and Interference with Their RNA Replication by Phage T4, Levinthal, Cyrus; Yarosh, Edward (Box 70)
  - [Experiment Notes], n.d.; Zahler, [Stanley A.] (Box 70)
  - Amber Mutants and Chain Termination in Vitro, Engelhardt, Dean L.; Konigsberg, William; Webster, Robert E.; Zinder, Norton D. (Box 70)
  - Ambert Mutants and Polarity in Vitro, Engelhardt, Dean L.; Webster, Robert E.; Zinder, Norton D. (Box 70)
  - A Bacteriophage Containing RNA, n.d.; Zinder, Norton D. (Box 70)
  - RNA Phages, n.d.; Zinder, Norton D. (Box 70)
  - Sexuality and Mating in Salmonella, Zinder, Norton D. (Box 70)
  - Speaking of Books: Historian as Citizen, 25 Sep. 1966; Zinn, Howard (Box 70)
  - A Study of the Urea Produced Sub-Units of Beta-Galactosidase, n.d.; Zipser, David (Box 70)
  - The Biochemistry of DNA Replication, n.d.; Hurwitz, Jerard; Shuman, Stewart; Zipursky, Larry (Box 70)
  - Factor Presence and Phage Attachment, 1965; Zwaig, N. (Box 70)
  - "Feedback Inhibition of Glycerol Kinase, a Catabolic Enzyme in Escherichia Coli", n.d.; Lin, E.C.C.; Zwaig, N. and E.C.C. Lin; Zwaig, N. (Box 70)
- Series V. Research notes, 1941-1979; 4.5 linear feet
  Loose notes and notebooks which are arranged by folder title and include the subjects of bacteria, colicins, microdermatology, phage, salmonella, Shigella coli, and viruses. Also in this series are notes taken by Luria at Cold Spring Harbor symposia and five folders of miscellaneous loose notes. Notebooks with no title have been filed as "Unidentified Notebook." Some notebooks have loose notes which are larger than the notebook pages. These notes were placed in folders and filed after each respective notebook. A photocopy of the first sheet of notes was placed at the appropriate notebook page with a cross reference.
  - Adsorption Data (Box 71)
  - Animal Viruses. Plant Viruses, [196-] (Box 71)
  - Antigens, Sep. 1961 (Box 71)
  - [Azaserine], 1979 (Box 71)
  - Bacterial Metabolism, n.d. (Box 71)
  - Bacterial Resistance, 1943 (Box 71)
  - Bacteriophage. Heat Experiments, [194-] (Box 71)
  - Bacteriophage. Irradiation, [194-] (Box 71)
  - [Beta-Galactosidase], n.d. (Box 71)
  - Blue #1, n.d. (Box 71)
  - Bowen's Thesis, n.d. (Box 71)
  - Brookhaven Symposium, 1959 (Box 71)
  - Calculations of 1-(1-e-D)n, n.d. (Box 71)
  - Cal. Tech. Meetings, Dec. 1956, Dec. 1957 (Box 71)
  - Chemistry Background, [197-] (Box 71)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Phage Meeting, 1965 (Box 72)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symposium, 1963 (Box 72)
  - Colicin Experiments, 1961 (Box 72)
  - Colicin Review, n.d. (Box 72)
  - [Colicins], 1964 (Box 72)
  - [Collagen], 1960 (Box 72)
  - Comments on Jane's Data; Bob's Data, Aug. 1959 (Box 72)
  - [Crosses], 1960 (Box 72)
  - C.S. Harbor, June 1961. Endicott House, June 1961. Perspectives in Virology III, Febr. 1967, 1961, 1967 (Box 72)
  - [CTP.H3], 1964 (Box 72)
  - Current Experiments, n.d. (Box 72)
  - DNA Transformation, n.d. (Box 73)
  - Emulsion, 1956-1957 (Box 73)
  - Experiments, 1963 (Box 73)
  - Experiments on c 35 Labeled Phage 22, 1954 (Box 73)
  - [Flagella], [197-] (Box 73)
  - Fluctuations of a1 in a Cultures, [194-] (Box 73)
  - [Fondation Royaumont--Notes], 1964 (Box 73)
  - Growth Curves of B Stocks, Mixtures and Mutants, 1946 (Box 73)
  - Hormones, n.d. (Box 73)
  - Host Induced Modification, 1959 (Box 73)
  - ICRF, 1973 (Box 73)
  - Inhibition of Tumor Induction in Swiss Mice by Human Gamma Globulins (Box 73)
  - Interference, 1941 (Box 73)
  - Johnson Strains, 1945 (Box 73)
  - [K-15], 1955 (Box 73)
  - [L], 1965 (Box 73)
  - [Lac Var], 1956 (Box 74)
  - L work, 1958 (Box 74)
  - Mammalian Cell Cycle. Mitosis, n.d. (Box 74)
  - Material Genetics. Cytochemistry, [196-] (Box 74)
  - Methods, n.d. (Box 74)
  - Meeting the Burns, Apr. 1964 (Box 74)
  - Megatherium Cultures, n.d. (Box 74)
  - Microdermatology, 1965 (Box 74)
  - Microdermatology, 1967 (Box 74)
  - Microdermatology, Oct. 1968 (Box 74)
  - Miscellaneous Experiments. T1 and T2: Temperature Experiments, 1943 (Box 74)
  - [Miscellaneous Notes], 1957-1970, n.d. (Box 75)
    5 Folders
  - Multiplicity Reactivation, 1946-1947 (Box 75)
  - Multiplicity Reactivation, 1947 (Box 76)
  - Nucleic Acids. Enzyme Forming Systems. Protein Structures, [196-] (Box 76)
  - [Nutrition], n.d. (Box 76)
  - Oak Ridge Meeting, 1954 (Box 76)
  - [P1], 1961 (Box 76)
  - P1 Transduction, 1958 (Box 76)
  - Partial Resistance, n.d. (Box 76)
  - Penicillins P and G Resistance, 1945 (Box 76)
  - Phage, n.d. (Box 76)
  - [Phage--Active and Inactive], 1947-1948 (Box 76)
  - Phage Colicines I, [196-] (Box 76)
  - Phage Colicines II, 1963 (Box 77)
  - Phage E15 Induction Clients (Box 77)
  - [Phage Experiments], 1955-1956 (Box 77)
  - [Phage Meeting at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory], 1949 (Box 77)
  - [Phage Meeting at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory], 25-27 Aug. 1954 (Box 77)
  - Phage Meeting at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, 24-26 Aug. 1956 (Box 77)
  - [Phage Meeting at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory], 27-30 Aug. 1957 (Box 77)
  - [Phage Meeting at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory], Aug. 1959 (Box 77)
  - [Phage Meeting at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory], 29-31 Aug. 1960 (Box 77)
  - Phage Mutations, [194-] (Box 77)
  - [Phosphatase], 1960 (Box 77)
  - [Phosphate Experiments], 1964 (Box 77)
  - Prophage Integration, n.d. (Box 77)
  - Random Readings, 1964 (Box 78)
  - Research Ideas, 1964 (Box 78)
  - Russian NA Model, 1958 (Box 78)
  - Salmonella, 1957-1958 (Box 78)
  - Salmonella - 22 Phage - Segregation Data, 1954 (Box 78)
  - Salmonella 78 Protoplasts, [195-] (Box 78)
  - Segregation Patterns, from Jane Adams, Aug. 1959 (Box 78)
  - Segregation Types, Oct. 1959 (Box 78)
  - Seminars. Discussions, [195-?] (Box 78)
  - Shigella Coli (Box 78)
    - Folder #1, 1956 (Box 78)
    - Folder #2, 1956 (Box 78)
    - Folder #3, 1957 (Box 79)
  - Shigella Hybrids, n.d. (Box 79)
  - Stock Phage Assays, n.d. (Box 79)
  - Synthetic Media Shigella, [195-] (Box 79)
  - Tabulation 1/g, [194-] (Box 79)
  - Transduction Episomes, n.d. (Box 79)
  - Tumors. Development. Antibody Synth., [195-] (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #1, 1959 (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #2, 1959 (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #3, [195-] (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #4, [196-] (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #5, [196-] (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #6, 1970 (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #7, 1971 (Box 79)
  - [Unidentified Notebook] #8, n.d. (Box 80)
  - [West Coast Phage Meeting], Feb. 1959 (Box 80)
- Series VI. Course materials, 1931-1991; 4.5 linear feet
  Lecture notes, exam and quiz questions, problem sets, lists of students registered for the courses, grade books, handouts, instructions for experiments, and reading lists. Course subjects include bacterial viruses, biochemistry, biophysics, freshman seminar, general biology, general microbiology, and microbial physiology.
  - Bacterial Biochemistry, 1953 (Box 81)
  - Bacterial Chemistry, 1948 (Box 81)
  - Bacterial Membranes 7.24, 1982 (Box 81)
  - Bacterial Viruses (Box 81)
    - Folder#1, 1957 (Box 81)
    - Folder#2, 1959 (Box 81)
    - Folder#3, 1960 (Box 81)
    - Folder#4, 1963 (Box 81)
    - Folder#5, n.d. (Box 81)
  - Bacteriology, 1952 (Box 81)
  - Bacteriology 100, n.d. (Box 81)
  - Bacteriology 104 (Box 81)
    - Folder#1, 1952 (Box 81)
    - Folder#2, n.d. (Box 81)
  - Bacteriology 203, 1960 (Box 81)
  - Bacteriology 258A, 1950 (Box 82)
  - Bacteriology 262, [194-] (Box 82)
  - Bacteriology 270, n.d. (Box 82)
  - Bacteriology 306 (Box 82)
    - Folder#1, 1951-1953 (Box 82)
    - Folder#2, 1954 (Box 82)
    - Folder#3, 1955 (Box 82)
    - Folder#4, 1955 (Box 82)
    - Folder#5, 1956 (Box 82)
    - Folder#6, 1957 (Box 82)
    - Folder#7, 1958 (Box 82)
    - Folder#8, 1959 (Box 82)
  - Bacteriology 320, n.d. (Box 83)
  - Bacteriology 331, 1941-1950 (Box 83)
  - Bacteriology 351 (Box 83)
    - Folder#1, 1951 (Box 83)
    - Folder#2, 1952 (Box 83)
    - Folder#3, [195-] (Box 83)
  - Bacteriology 420, n.d. (Box 83)
  - Bacteriology 425 (Box 83)
    - Folder#1, 1951 (Box 83)
    - Folder#2, 1953 (Box 83)
  - Bacteriology 451 (Box 83)
    - Folder#1, 1954 (Box 83)
    - Folder#2, 1956 (Box 83)
    - Folder#3, 1957 (Box 83)
    - Folder#4, 1958 (Box 83)
  - Bacteriology and Hygiene, 1931-1942 (Box 83)
  - Biochemistry, n.d. (Box 83)
  - Biochemistry 203 (Box 83)
    - Folder#1, 1969 (Box 83)
    - Folder#2, 1971 (Box 83)
  - Biology Preliminary Examination, 1965 (Box 83)
  - Biology: Roots and Branches, 1987 (Box 83)
  - Biology Seminar 7.32 (Box 84)
    - Folder#1, 1967 (Box 84)
    - Folder#2, 1968 (Box 84)
    - Folder#3, 1972, n.d. (Box 84)
  - Biophysics 202, [195-] (Box 84)
  - Biophysics 206, n.d. (Box 84)
  - Chemistry 5.43, 1962 (Box 84)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Phage Course, 1956 (Box 84)
  - Cytology of Bacteria, 1948 (Box 84)
  - Developmental Biology 7.04, 1972 (Box 84)
  - Developmental Genetics 7.32, 1972 (Box 84)
  - Freshman Seminar (Box 84)
    - Folder#1, 1962 (Box 84)
    - Folder#2, 1963 (Box 84)
    - Folder#3, 1970 (Box 84)
    - Folder#4, 1978 (Box 84)
    - Folder#5, 1985 (Box 84)
    - Folder#6, 1986 (Box 84)
  - General Biology 7.01 (Box 84)
    - Folder#1, 1968 (Box 84)
    - Folder#2, 1969 (Box 84)
    - Folder#3, 1970 (Box 84)
    - Folder#4, 1971 (Box 84)
    - Folder#5, 1972 (Box 84)
    - Folder#6, 1973 (Box 85)
    - Folder#7, 1974 (Box 85)
    - Folder#8, 1975 (Box 85)
    - Folder#9, 1976 (Box 85)
    - Folder#10, 1977 (Box 85)
    - Folder#11, 1979 (Box 85)
    - Folder#12, 1980 (Box 85)
    - Folder#13, 1981 (Box 85)
    - Folder#14, 1982 (Box 86)
    - Folder#15, 1984 (Box 86)
    - Folder#16, n.d. (Box 86)
  - General Microbiology 7.21 (Box 86)
    - Folder#1, 1960-1967 (Box 86)
    - Folder#2, 1968-1974 (Box 86)
    - Folder#3, n.d. (Box 86)
  - Grade Books (Box 86)
    - Folder#1, 1959-1971 (Box 86)
    - Folder#2, 1971-1975 (Box 86)
    - Folder#3, 1976-1980 (Box 87)
    - Folder#4, 1981-1984, n.d. (Box 87)
  - Harvard Medical School, 1989-1991, n.d. (Box 87)
  - Interaction Between Animal Viruses and Host Cells--ICRO/Unesco Course, 1964 (Box 87)
  - Literature Course, 1966-1969 (Box 87)
  - Microbial Biochemistry 358, 1949 (Box 87)
  - Microbial Genetics, 1963 (Box 87)
  - Microbial Physiology 7.21 (Box 87)
    - Folder#1, 1972 (Box 87)
    - Folder#2, 1974 (Box 88)
    - Folder#3, 1977 (Box 88)
    - Folder#4, 1978 (Box 88)
    - Folder#5, 1979 (Box 88)
    - Folder#6, 1981 (Box 88)
    - Folder#7, 1982-1984 (Box 88)
    - Folder#8, 1985 (Box 88)
    - Folder#9, 1986 (Box 88)
  - Microbiology, [194-], 1961-1962, n.d. (Box 88)
  - Microbiology 7.22, 1961 (Box 88)
  - Microbiology 7.93 (Box 88)
    - Folder#1, 1958 (Box 88)
    - Folder#2, 1971 (Box 88)
  - Microbiology Laboratory 7.93, 1960 (Box 88)
  - Microbiology Seminar 7.31 (Box 88)
    - Folder#1, 1961-1966 (Box 88)
    - Folder#2, 1967 (Box 88)
  - Mind from Matter?, 1990 (Box 88)
  - Molecular Biophysics--Course at International School of Physics, 1964 (Box 89)
  - Molecular Genetics 7.86, 1965, 1969 (Box 89)
  - Paramagnetic Resonance Spectroscopy, n.d. (Box 89)
  - Phage Seminar 7.25, 1985 (Box 89)
  - Phycomyces Course, Cold Spring Harbor, 1965 (Box 89)
  - Physiology, n.d. (Box 89)
  - Preliminary Examinations, 1951, 1963, 1967 (Box 89)
  - Rassegna Della Stampa, [1986] (Box 89)
  - Selected Methods in Bacterial Genetics, Jun. 1960 (Box 89)
  - Virus Laboratory, 1949 (Box 89)
- Series VII. Photographs, 1957-1982; 8.25 linear feet
  Prints and negatives, many of which are illustrations for articles. Folders containing prints of Luria include: American Society for Microbiology; Karl Taylor Compton Lectureship; and Osaka University. There are a number of folders containing unidentified figures, probably published in articles and books. Also included in this series are four boxes of lantern slides and one box of 2x2 inch slides. The slides seem to be visual aids for lectures and illustrations for articles.
  - Affidavit in Lieu of Passport (Box 90)
    See Ser.IIb, same title
  - An Amber Suppressor tRNA Gene Derived by Site Specific Mutagenesis: Cloning and Function in Mammalian Cells, [1982] (Box 90)
  - American Society for Microbiology, n.d. (Box 90)
  - Autoradiographs Relating Nucleic Acid Metabolism to the Appearance of Intracellular Vaccinia Virus, 1961 (Box 90)
  - Beta-Galactosidase, n.d. (Box 90)
  - The Cleveland Clinic Foundation, 1982 (Box 90)
  - Colicins, 1964 (Box 90)
  - Karl Taylor Compton Lectureship, 1959 (Box 90)
  - Electron Micrographs, n.d. (Box 90)
  - Equipment, 1965 (Box 90)
  - Isolation and Characterization of a Mutant Colicin E2 (Box 90)
  - Isolation and Characterization of DNA Sequences Amplified in Multidrug Resistant Hamster Cells (Box 90)
  - Isolation of Bacteriophages by Polyethelene-Glycol-Dextransulfate Two Phase Systems and by Peg Precipitation: Methods of General Applicability, [1967] (Box 90)
  - Isolation of Tolerant Mutants, [1968?] (Box 90)
  - Keleman, Mary V., [1957] (Box 90)
  - Luria, Salvador Edward--Passport, 1983 (Box 90)
  - Mutations, n.d. (Box 90)
  - Nobel Prize, 1969 (Box 90)
  - Osaka University, [1965] (Box 90)
  - P1, 1961 (Box 90)
  - Phage, [1957] (Box 90)
  - Sagik, Bernard P., 1953 (Box 90)
  - Shub, n.d. (Box 90)
  - Stable Expression and Replication of Hepatitis B Virus Genome in an Integrated State in a Human Hepatoma Cell Line Transfected with the Cloned Viral DNA (Box 90)
  - Transparency Roll, n.d. (Box 90)
  - Unidentified Figures, n.d. (Box 90)
    4 Folders
  - Use of a Foreign Epitope as a Tag for the Localization of Minor Proteins within a Cell: The Case of the Immunity Protein to Colicin A, [198-] (Box 91)
- Series I-VII. Oversized materials (Oversize Series I-VII:1)
  - Series I, Correspondence
    - McCarthy, Eugene, 1967; Oversize
    - Rubin, Harry, 24 Feb. 1958
  - Series IIa, Subject Files
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1959; 2 items
    - Brussels Universal and International Exhibition, 1958
    - Cuba, 1962
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1960
    - Nuclear Arms, 1964, 1969, [1982]
    - The Salk Institute for Biological Studies--Workshop on the Problems of Drugs and Drug Addiction
    - A Slot Machine, A Broken Test Tube, 1984-1985
    - Vietnam, 1964-1972
    - Series IV, Works by Others
    - Bresch, Carsten
    - Zum Paarungsmechanismus von Bacteriophagen, 1955
    - Transparency Roll, n.d.
    - Unidentified Figures, n.d.
  - Series IIb, Personal Materials
    - Università Degli Studi di Torino, 1938